Guide to the Utah labor archive audio-visual collection 1948-1961
Multimedia Archives, J. Willard Marriott Library, University of Utah
Utah labor archive audio-visual collection
1948-1961
University of Utah Libraries, Special Collections Audio Visual Archives Special Collections 295 South 1500 East Salt Lake City, Utah 84112-0860 (801) 581-8864
A0199
Richardson, Reed C., 1917-
77 phonograph records, 3 16mm films
The Utah labor archive audio-visual collection (1948-1961) consists of audio recordings of speeches and songs and informational films relating to labor unions in Utah and the United States at large.
Historical Note
The Univertsity of Utah was designated the official labor archives of the State of Utah in 1971. The paper records and audio-visual items created or kept by various Utah labor unions have been deposited here.
The Utah labor archive audio-visual collection (1948-1961) consists of 77 audio recordings of speeches and songs relating to labor unions in Utah and the United States at large and 3 16mm films about the labor movement.
The majority of the materials are arranged by subject matter and format.
Materials must be used on-site; no use of original material, access copies will be made available for viewing. Five business days advanced notice required. Access to parts of this collection may be restricted under provisions of state or federal law, condition of the material, or by donor.
See also the Utah labor archives (Ms 13) in the Manuscripts Division of Special Collections.
Hoffa, James R. (James Riddle), 1913-; Labor unions--United States--History--Sources; Labor unions--United States--Songs and music; Labor Unions; Moving Images; Sound Recordings; Moving images; Sound recordings
- Talks by labor leaders and others, 51 phonograph records (Box 1)
  - International Brotherhood of Teamsters, special events report: Unions and ex-convicts, undated (Disc 1-2)
    2 copies
  - International Brotherhood of Teamsters: International Control Commission (ICC) unfairly favors railroads, 1961 April 09 (Disc 3)
    General President James R. Hoffa
  - International Brotherhood of Teamsters, special events report: The dangers of the Kennedy-Irvin Bill, 1959 June 10 (Disc 4-5)
  - William Green: final conference speech, 1949 July 20 (Disc 6)
  - Image of freedom: 20 years of the Congress of Industrial Organizations (CIO), undated (Disc 7-8)
  - International Brotherhood of Teamsters: Safety truck week, June 6-11 (Disc 9)
  - Voice of Franklin Delano Roosevelt: A few quotations from his speeches., undated (Disc 10-11)
  - Labor's League for Political Education (LLPE) parts 1-4, circa 1950 (Disc 12)
    Senator Hubert Humphrey at National Conference of the LLPE.
  - Labor's League for Political Education parts 2, 5, circa 1950 (Disc 13)
  - Labor's League for Political Education parts 3, 6, circa 1950 (Disc 14)
    Senator Hubert Humphrey at National Conference of the LLPE: "We can win in 1950."
  - Clegg-Vest Act hearings, 1947 (Disc 15-25)
    Hearings about Utah's labor-management relations act held at the Newhouse Hotel during the 1947 legislative session.
  - "What I would say", 1949 July 23 (Disc 26-27)
    Address by Dave Beck over Columbia Broadcasting System (CBS).
  - Unidentified meetings, undated (Disc 28-51)
- Songs of the labor movement, 19 phonograph records (Box 2)
  - "A Promise ain't a promise anymore" and "You gotta go down", undated (Disc 1-2)
    Joe Glazer and the PAC Bucks
  - American industrial ballads, undated (Disc 3-4)
  - "Ballads for sectarians" and "Songs of the Wobblies", undated (Disc 5)
    The Wobblies are the Industrial Workers of the World (IWW)
  - "The great American bum" and other hobo and migratory worker's songs, undated (Disc 6-7)
  - "Joe McCarthy's band" and "The giveaway boys in Washington", undated (Disc 8-9)
    Joe Glazer
  - "Love that team", undated (Disc 10-11)
  - "The original talking union" and other union songs, undated (Disc 12-13)
  - "Solidarity" and "Give-away boys", undated (Disc 14-15)
  - The songs of Joe Hill, undated (Disc 16-17)
  - The songs of the Wobblies, undated (Disc 18-19)
- Miscellaneous talks, stories and films, 7 phonograph records, 3 16mm films (Box 3)
  - Phonograph records
    - Vote 1948 (Disc 1)
    - Dave Beck speaks on the Boeing problem, 1949 June 01 (Disc 2)
    - Dave Beck speaks on National Trade Conference meetings, undated (Disc 3)
    - "It's a crime to organize" and "The Oakville story", undated (Disc 4)
    - "The Americanism of Mr. Mudget" and "Mr. Pine faces life", undated (Disc 5)
    - "Big union" and "The plot to overthrow Lincoln", undated (Disc 6)
    - Park City, Utah miner's broadcast, undated (Disc 7)
  - 16mm films
    - The unions, undated (Reel 1)
    - Wonders of automation, undated (Reel 2)
    - A Bench in the Park, undated (Reel 3)
      Contains a trailer of a report by Wayne Morse